what's going on ladies and gentlemen
welcome back to another one and as you
can see we're on the water we're ready
to do another product review for you
guys I'm super excited about it we're
actually on the pontoon today we're not
in the kayak and we're not in the
fishing boat I thought it would be fun
to switch it up a little bit we're
trying to catch bass again today um
maybe some Pike and that kind of thing
but let me grab this reel and I'll show
you guys what we're going to be
reviewing and I'm super excited about
this product I've wanted to review it
for a long time it's actually another
fishing reel and this is a fishing reel
that I had when I was really little it
was one probably one of the first reels
I ever owned and I got a new one and I'm
super excited about it it's the Shimano
Sedona FL and these things have been
around for a very long time and I'm
pretty excited for it it's the Shimano
Sedona FL 2500 series so should be a
good reel for you know bass fishing
Walle fishing you should be able to
catch the bigger fish with it and they
also sell it in all different sizes you
can buy it in a thousand size rod and 30
500 4500 that kind of thing so uh we're
going to talk about this thing we're
going to break it down and tell you guys
what I think of it so let's jump into it
okay before we break this thing down
guys today we're throwing a weightless
Texas Rig and we're going to be trying
to catch some bass with it I do have
like a pretty long ribbon tail a yum
ribbon tail it's just a green color and
hopefully we can catch some fish on it
now my first initial thoughts on this
reel it feels a little heavy I'm not
going to lie as I start casting it it
feels a little bit heavier I just did a
review on the PC fun carbon x
2000 and uh it felt a lot lighter than
this I don't remember this reel being
this heavy but maybe it's just in my
head right now I just got to use a
little bit it does feel super smooth
reeling it in I mean it feels really
good so that is promising The Reeling
speed seems
good casting is pretty good granted this
is really weightless there's not a whole
lot of weight to it so you know any
casting distance with it is probably
pretty decent I just put some 10 pound
monofilament on here I was hoping to
kind of have this as my finesse reel you
know Slow Rolling sink goes off the
bottom and that kind of thing so we'll
see how it goes so I just picked this
reel up on Amazon it's just the fastest
and easiest way to get it it is a little
pricey at $79.99 I do hope that this
thing kind of holds up to its name
Shimano Sedonas have been around for a
long time and and so far it seems to be
pretty good I like that it's all kind of
metal there's no it doesn't have a
plasticky feel to it and I think they
changed that a little bit I I believe
these reels used to have a bit of a
plasticky feel and this one feels pretty
good the drag system seems really really
nice I got to test out the drag a little
bit more I'm going to probably loosen it
and if we can hook up on a fish just
kind of see how that looks at a first
glance this reel seems to have a lot of
positives for it it's really cast nice
even with with a super light line and
that kind of thing I do like this big
knob at the top for the drag that's kind
of nice you can change it pretty easily
on the fly if you're catching a fish
like most spinning reels you can
interchange which side you want your
reel to be on I reel with my left hand
so I switched it over because it did
come on this side but obviously that's
pretty typical there is a reverse on it
so you can flip it over and the spool
will go both ways which is pretty
typical I feel like a lot of reels are
doing away with that but these guys
haven't yet so I mean I think it's
pretty fair to say though that Shimano
has been around for a long time and
they're known for Quality Parts actually
have I have two Shimano in the boat
right now my Shimano curado DC and this
guy so Shimano are pretty great but yeah
this reel weighs in at 8 oz which is
pretty decent I do have some other reels
that are a little bit lighter than this
but it does seem to be made of quality
parts and I love how smooth The Reel is
it reels in like incredibly smooth so
that's a huge positive but for $80 I
would expect that you know the mono on
here seems to be pretty solid I think
you could throw a pretty heavy braided
line on this and do pretty successful as
well which is something nice um I put
braid on so many of my reels that I just
wanted to have at least one Reel with
just you know mono or fluorocarbon and
this is the one I picked it does real
smooth because that's a pretty expensive
spinning reel I will say we just move
spots a little bit but I will say that
if there's one thing that Shimano is
known for is the but they make reels
that last a long time okay I mean I had
a Shimano Sedona um I'm not sure if it
was an FL or what it was but when I was
little and that reel still works it's
just so old now that I just decided to
upgrade to a you know newer one and I
have a lot of other reels that I use but
Shimano last a long time so if you're
looking for a reel that's going to stand
the test of time and honestly just make
a good quality reel for you I would
definitely check out this reel I have
brand new line on this reel and I
haven't had a lick of problems with it
there's been no backlashes of any sort
and it's definitely just been doing a
good job oh oh there's a bite I don't
have it it's so windy out here holy
canoli I'm sorry if the wind audio is
bad guys it's like crazy windy out here
I might have to go tuck away and find a
calmer
spot I think we're going to go do that
this spot is really good but we got a
typically can be really good but we're
going to go we're going to find a little
calmer spot so one of the reasons this
reel is going to last so long for
anybody that uses it is there's four
bearings in this reel and three of which
are designed for anti-corrosion so
they're not going to corrode over time
and they should last for a lot of years
I mean I know people that have used
their shanos like these ones for 10 20
plus years and they just last and then
there is a fourth bearing and it's just
a roller bearing and that's probably for
the you know smooth reeling and casting
and that kind of thing but all around if
you're looking for a reel that's going
to stand the test of time the Shimano
Sedona is definitely one to look into I
will link it in the description down
below if you guys want to check it
[Music]
out oh this is a big one it's a big one
yep get them out get them out come on
holy canoli this is a big one
oh
wow come on buddy holy cow I might need
to up my line on this reel the drag
feels
good it's handling them real nice oh
don't let them under the boat come on
now wa that's a nice fish couple pounder
oh yeah yeah I might need to get some
heavier line for this reel but check
that out guys that's a pretty nice fish
we'll take it not a giant but you know
he fought really well so we'll take that
that's a nice one and I must say The
Reel did a great job but we're going to
get this guy off and send them back and
get back to the
review see you later big
guy one thing I did want to note guys we
were doing a giveaway for the Abu Garcia
Vengeance I'm going to link the winner
to that reel or excuse me for that combo
down in the comments down below so make
sure you check that out and you might
have won yourself a new uh rod and reil
setup so check it out
and all around though guys I think this
reel is very positive I think for $80
it's a little pricey but you do pay for
that because this reel is designed to
last a really really long time it's not
going to degrade over time and you can
probably use it for many many years to
come so that is something that you pay
for um and it does seem to be really
nice it reels super smooth it cast's
good I just put brand new line on it and
I haven't had a single backlash or
anything sometimes you know it just
takes a little bit for that line to get
wet and get on the real but it's been
positive completely positive things to
say about it the drag is smooth all that
kind of stuff so I hope you guys enjoyed
this video and if you did make sure you
smash the Subscribe button and like the
video because we're going to be doing a
lot more product reviews like this one
so I hope you guys enjoyed the video and
we'll see you in the next one peace